<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-27T13:38:08-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Elizabeth Case</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Elizabeth Case, adapted from Paul Le</name></author><entry><title type="html">Zotero as a Reference Manager</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ZoteroIntro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zotero as a Reference Manager" /><published>2021-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ZoteroIntro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ZoteroIntro">&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&quot;https://elizabethcase.github.io/tools/ObsidianForPhDs.html&quot;&gt;Obsidian can be a useful tool&lt;/a&gt; for managing your personal, day-to-day notes, the bulk of knowledge in a science PhD comes from papers. A reference management system is crucial for saving papers you read or plan to read, and organizing and exporting citations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than a personal file management system (e.g. saving papers in folders of your choosing), there are two main software options: Mendeley and Zotero. Mendeley is owned by Elsevier, one of the largest scientific publishing companies in the world. Zotero is open source. In general, I try to use open source products where I can, because #powertothepeople, and open source developers tend to be more responsive to user needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Zotero is an open-source resource manager - a place for you to store, organize, sort and cite documents like journal articles, book chapters, software, etc. For ease, I will just refer to any and all reference material as “papers”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;zotero-basics&quot;&gt;Zotero Basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;folder-organization&quot;&gt;Folder organization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zotero is organized into Libraries, which can be further subdivided into groups, sub-groups, etc. Personally, I think it is helpful to have two sets of folders in your library:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;one that contains all the papers for a particular research project, paper, or thesis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;another that groups papers by topic / keyword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another useful folder for organization is the &lt;strong&gt;inbox / to-read&lt;/strong&gt; (just make sure to refile papers you read!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have folders for papers I used to prep for my qualifying exam, paper collections from various seminars &amp;amp; classes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;notes-tags-etc&quot;&gt;Notes, tags, etc&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each indexed item, you can add your own notes (e.g. from reading the paper), tags, etc. I personally don’t use tags. The search function, combined with filing away in the correct folder, is good enough for me. I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; use notes – generally highlights and comments from reading the paper. I have started to translate these notes into Obsidian when there’s a paper I really need to know well. The ability to extract annotations is expanded on below in plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;plug-ins&quot;&gt;Plug-ins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you can add files to, export citations from, etc manually  Zotero, a few plug-ins increase it’s usefulness significantly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Browser extension&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text editor integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Annotation extraction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;browser-extension&quot;&gt;Browser extension&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The browser plug-in connects your desktop library to the internet. When you access a resource you want to save online – a paper, an article, a piece of software – you click the Zotero button, choose the folder you’re going to save it in, and voila, the PDF is downloaded and the metadata has been extracted, and it’s all indexed in your library. Absolutely crucial to my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/download/&quot;&gt;Firefox extension can be downloaded&lt;/a&gt; directly from the Zotero website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;text-editor-integration&quot;&gt;Text editor integration&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have written both of my journal papers, and my exam papers, in World. Yeah, I know, maybe I should use latex, finally commit to Overleaf, etc. Perhaps I will get there eventually. But for now, I do my writing in Word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Zotero, you can insert citations &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt;, e.g. as you’re typing away. They also have extensions for LibreOffice and Google docs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/support/word_processor_integration&quot;&gt;Here’s a link to the plug-ins&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;annotation-extraction&quot;&gt;Annotation extraction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zotfile.com/#extract-pdf-annotations&quot;&gt;Zotfile&lt;/a&gt; is the newest addition to my workflow, and it is a homerun. When reading a paper, I usually&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;print the paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;highlgiht and annotate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;transfer those highlights and notes to the digital PDF&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing I want to do after all those steps is then spend time copying and pasting those notes and highlights into the Notes section of Zotero or into a file in Obsidian. Now I don’t have to – Zotfile will automatically extract highliights and notes &lt;em&gt;by color&lt;/em&gt; into Zotero. These can then be copied into Obsidian, or left for your future self in Zotero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zotfile.com/#extract-pdf-annotations&quot;&gt;Zotfile’s documentation&lt;/a&gt; is pretty thorough, but to install, right click &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;download --&amp;gt; save link as&lt;/code&gt;. Then open up Zotero. Choose  &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Tools --&amp;gt; Add Ons&lt;/code&gt; from the top menu. Click on the little gear button in the upper right hand corner, then click &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;install add-on from file&lt;/code&gt; and choose the Zotfile xpi file you just downloaded. There’s lots of ways to customize your Zotfile experience; I’ve found it most reliable to just leave things in their default settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use Zotfile for tablet &amp;lt;–&amp;gt; computer PDF syncing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;other-useful-plugins&quot;&gt;Other useful plugins&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://retorque.re/zotero-better-bibtex/&quot;&gt;Better BibTex&lt;/a&gt; (more useful citation keys)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/argenos/zotero-mdnotes&quot;&gt;Mdnotes for Zoter&lt;/a&gt;o (export as markdown)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leonkt/zotero-memento/releases/tag/v1.0.1&quot;&gt;Zotero Memento &lt;/a&gt;(saves webpages robustly, e.g. through multiple sources like internet archive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Elizabeth Case</name></author><category term="tools" /><category term="reference-manager" /><category term="tech" /><category term="tools" /><category term="knowledge-management" /><category term="zotero" /><summary type="html">While Obsidian can be a useful tool for managing your personal, day-to-day notes, the bulk of knowledge in a science PhD comes from papers. A reference management system is crucial for saving papers you read or plan to read, and organizing and exporting citations.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/zotero_library.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/zotero_library.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Obsidian, the answer to note-taking for the PhD?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ObsidianForPhDs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Obsidian, the answer to note-taking for the PhD?" /><published>2021-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ObsidianForPhDs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ObsidianForPhDs">&lt;p&gt;My whole life I’ve struggled to stay organized, and the latest iteration of this battle is notetaking for knowledge building – a.k.a. how to learn and remember what I learn for my PhD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, I’ve realized that I need two things from a notetaking system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;frictionless consistency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;multiple modes of organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my masters, I created a daily template in TextEdit that I would copy to a new document each morning. But while this standardized my notes, the copying was tedious, and it was difficult to find information after writing it down – defeating the point of taking notes in the first place. &lt;strong&gt;In fact, I find that if I can’t find information I’ve taken notes on, it makes taking future notes even harder: putting in that time feels futile.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But organization is key to developing a knowledge base, and in essence, that is exactly what a PhD is:&lt;/strong&gt; developing a knowledge base that allows you to hypothesize, make inferences, extrapolate, connect. Daily notes, project notes, notes on papers, code documentation – all of it should lubricate the wheels of future thinking / work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest, and most promising of these efforts, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;, a markdown-based app that enables consistency, provides a multiplicity of search functions and note connections, and can be modified to your needs (and tastes) through user-developed plugins and custom CSS. Writing/note-taking should be pleasurable! Customization goes a long way toward this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;main-features&quot;&gt;Main features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for a few key features in an app, and Obsidian has them all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;local, universal file storage&lt;/strong&gt;– none of this garbage about needing to be online to access your notes (Roam, Notion), or having your notes stored in some proprietary format (Evernote). Instead, all of Obsidian’s notes (and other similar programs, like Zettlr) are stored as markdown files.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;many different ways to search&lt;/strong&gt; – the first level of accessing information is through file hierarchies, but Obsidian also offers:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;excellent search capabilities:&lt;/em&gt; the search is very good at finding whatever you’re looking for (and sorts/selects by tags, content, filename, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;flawless internal linking:&lt;/em&gt; one of the backbones of Obsidian, it is incredibly easy to link not only to other files in your “Vault” (file hierarchy), but to individual sections/paragraphs within them. Just type double brackets &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[[ file name ]]&lt;/code&gt; and start typing the file name; Obsidian will automatically link to it or create a new file if it doesn’t yet exist. This makes creating or referencing files &lt;em&gt;super easy&lt;/em&gt; and really helps me stay organized.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;backlinks:&lt;/em&gt; the hot new thing for notetaking apps, backlinks show you which files link to the one your on; this can sometimes lead to interesting insights, e.g. when multiple files from different trains of thought lead to the same place&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;networked graphs:&lt;/em&gt; building off internal file links, networked graphs show you how all your files are connected (which files are linked to who). fun to click around, find random connections, follow pathways&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;tags&lt;/em&gt;: search by tags, and/or check the tag pane for a list of tags in your vault. Tags are really useful for keeping track of different projects &amp;amp; paper sections. My only issue is that it’s easy to mistype tags, and mistyped tags still get added to the main tag list.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;external file linking&lt;/strong&gt; – I am mad-good at getting distracted, so I want to be able to click on a reference and have that file open, whether it’s a PDF, a piece of code in Matlab, or my thesis proposal in Powerpoint. In Obsidian, you can do this! As simple as linking to a website: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[text](file:///User/... )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;daily templates&lt;/strong&gt; – this is a plug-in (more below), but essential (see above: mad-good procrastinator). I made &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Elizabethcase/elizabethcase.github.io/blob/master/assets/docs/DailyTemplateObsidian.md?raw=true&quot;&gt;a daily template&lt;/a&gt;. Now I just click a single button for a fresh day’s worth of notes!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zotero integration&lt;/strong&gt; – it’s not a perfect plug-in, but I can import my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zotero.org/&quot;&gt;Zotero&lt;/a&gt; library, and cite papers directly in Obsidian. This is super useful when I’m close-reading a paper, and will probably get more useful as I start to write my dissertation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;flexibility/open source&lt;/strong&gt; – this wasn’t a &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; but it’s a huge bonus – Obsidian’s user base is active and constantly developing plug-ins for the app that really improve day-to-day usage. Plus I can customize the CSS so that my workspace is a pleasure to write in &amp;amp; with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;plug-ins&quot;&gt;Plug-ins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obsidian has both core and third-party plug-ins. I depend on a few for my workload:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;core-plug-ins&quot;&gt;Core plug-ins&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daily Note’s&lt;/em&gt; – with a click, create a new daily note from a template that you build. Many ideas around daily notetaking exist online, do whatever is simplest for you and stay consistent. Mine has a link to the previous day and the next day, a log of my sleep and emotional state, and four header sections: To Do, Morning Intake, Work, Writing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Graph View&lt;/em&gt; – I love a visual representation.. and a way to just click around with abandon to jog my memory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tag Pane&lt;/em&gt; – in particular, this plug-in makes it really easy to track notes from projects, specially across Daily Notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;third-party-plug-ins&quot;&gt;Third-party plug-ins&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advanced Tables&lt;/em&gt; – makes using markdown tables a breeze&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Calendar&lt;/em&gt; – sometimes I want to generate a Daily Note for sometime in the future; this let’s me do that&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Citations&lt;/em&gt; – Zotero integration, holy grail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CSS snippets&lt;/em&gt; – oh boy does my workspace look good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paste URL into selection&lt;/em&gt; – copy a link, select a word,  ctrl+shift+v, voila&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sliding Panes&lt;/em&gt; – allows you to have a couple of panes open at once, which makes for easier referencing and note building&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-features-that-improve-obsidian&quot;&gt;Other features that improve Obsidian:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://espanso.org/&quot;&gt;Espanso&lt;/a&gt; – a text expander
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:bc&lt;/code&gt;  (short for breadcrumb) at the top of my Daily Notes template auto fills so that I can click to yesterday or tomorrow, e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;[[20210124-Sun|&amp;lt;&amp;lt; Yesterday]] | [[20210126-Tue|Tommorrow &amp;gt;&amp;gt;]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:zoom&lt;/code&gt; writes out my personal zoom link&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:orcid&lt;/code&gt; writes out my orcid number&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:cell&lt;/code&gt; writes out my cell number&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I also use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:meet&lt;/code&gt; so that a meeting template auto generates, looks like:
        &lt;h3 id=&quot;meeting&quot;&gt;Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tags:&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Zoom link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Agenda link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Attendees:&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Tasks:&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Notes:&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;features-i-would-love-to-seeuse&quot;&gt;Features I would love to see/use:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scheduled reviews of notes - give me an easy way to do a weekly/ monthly review, e.g. autopopulate a note with that week’s or month’s Daily Notes. There’s probably a hacky way to do this with regex + templates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Translate markdown in realtime: Obsidian has two modes, edit and preview. Edit shows most of the markdown. Preview translates the markdown. I wish Obsidian would take a note from Zettlr and just make the markdown disappear as I write. You can do this with css customization, but it often doesn’t work well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A post is coming soon about how to set up and use Obsidian. I’d love to hear about what you use to take notes! If you have any tips, comments or questions, feel free to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elizabeth Case</name></author><category term="tools" /><category term="note-taking" /><category term="tech" /><category term="tools" /><category term="knowledge-management" /><category term="obsidian" /><summary type="html">My whole life I’ve struggled to stay organized, and the latest iteration of this battle is notetaking for knowledge building – a.k.a. how to learn and remember what I learn for my PhD.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Choosing a Mechanical Keyboard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/MechanicalKeyboards" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Choosing a Mechanical Keyboard" /><published>2021-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/MechanicalKeyboards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/MechanicalKeyboards">&lt;p&gt;I went down a narrow but deep rabbit hole this last weekend, after my partner’s five-year old (external) Apple keyboard crapped out on me. My laptop keyboard has been going down the drain for a while now too – it’s a 2016 Macbook Pro, which has the now-outdated butterfly keys that are notorious for breaking. My &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt; keys fall out regularly now, and the rest of the keyboard is on its way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been interested in mechanical keyboards for a while. On top of nostalgic memories of clacking away on old keyboards in my dad’s office (which is, to this day, &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; with technology), I’m interested in the physical experience of interacting with a digital/virtual/software-focused “space”. I think a lot about what is on my desk or where I am writing/working and how the environment contributes to the experience of work. Part of this is due to the fact that ergonomics is a nightmare for someone as small as me (5’2”). As far as I can tell, there is no (reasonably priced) office furniture made for people my size, so working often ends up being uncomfortable (feet cant’t reach the ground, or I type at shoulder level, or both), or hacked (a cardboard box under my feet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I haven’t put much effort into the keyboard, even though along with the mouse (I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/microsoft-wireless-mobile-mouse-3500/8tvskjhgskkc?cid=msft_web_collection&amp;amp;activetab=pivot%3aoverviewtab&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; – it’s portable, reliable, cheap, battery lasts forever), it is the physical tool I use most in my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some advantages of mechanical keyboards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a lot of their parts are fixable or replaceable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they come in myriad sizes and shapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they are built to last&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and most importantly, they can vastly improve your typing experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many cheaper keyboards require people to &lt;strong&gt;overtype&lt;/strong&gt;, or press down too hard or too far, which can be fatiguing for folks who spend a lot of time on the computer, e.g. me. With mechanical keyboards, you can choose what kind of switches you want. Where keycaps are the aesthetic covering, &lt;strong&gt;switches are what actually register when you press down on a key&lt;/strong&gt;. Some switches only register at the bottom of a keypress (improving accuracy by preventing mistypes), others give tactile feedback when the keystroke registers (improving speed and requiring less typing force from you). For those who game regularly or competitively, or folks who type a lot, these decisions can change the way you interact with your computer. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mechanicalkeyboards.com/switches/&quot;&gt;Switches are known by their color type&lt;/a&gt;), e.g. brown, red, clear, and these all indicate different properties like the force it takes to press the switch down, and whether the switch gives any feedback or makes noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into the search with a couple of desired features: a smaller board (without a numberpad, a.k.a. a tenkeyless) that would allow me to have a more ergonomic set up with my mouse; tactile feedback (clicky or a feeling of pressing the key); and wireless connectivity (not a requirement, but a want).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I first turned to my dad, a retired technology writer. He suggested the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.logitechg.com/en-us/products/gaming-keyboards/g915-tkl-wireless.html&quot;&gt;Logitech G915TKL &lt;/a&gt; as having a superior typing experience (e.g. you don’t have to press hard or far). At $229, these boards were a little pricier than I, a graduate student, was willing to spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I turned to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/MechanicalKeyboards/&quot;&gt;mechanical keyboard subreddit&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the usual places for tech recommendations: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/reviews/our-favorite-mechanical-keyboards/&quot;&gt;Wirecutter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/gallery/best-keyboards/&quot;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;, random blogs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://drop.com/home&quot;&gt;Drop&lt;/a&gt;, etc. I remembered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eGXbCUXAKYs&quot;&gt;Ali Abdaal’s Youtube video&lt;/a&gt; where he had recommended a very aesthetic keyboard (to his credit, I searched “london doctor productivity”, which was all i could remember about him, and he showed up). That took me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://iqunix.store/&quot;&gt;IQUNIX&lt;/a&gt;, but again these were a bit out of my price rage (on the order of $175-199). A bit of Google searching led me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://mechanicalkeyboards.com/&quot;&gt;Mechanicalkeyboards.com &lt;/a&gt;, which sells keyboards but also has a wealth of information. A lot of their most aesthetic keyboards sell out regularly, but restock often, too. The most common introductory keyboards are made by Ducky ($99) and Leopold ($119-150). I ~almost~ went with this &lt;a href=&quot;https://mechanicalkeyboards.com/shop/index.php?l=product_detail&amp;amp;p=4560&quot;&gt;Leopold&lt;/a&gt;, which got great reviews, but then remembered I had a mac and also that keyboard is not wireless, which was a bit of a downside. On reddit, a lot of folks recommend Keychrons for introductory mechanical keyboards for mac users, and after weighing price, quality, user-friendliness, etc, I ultimately went with them, buying for $99 (incl shipping):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.keychron.com/products/keychron-k2-hot-swappable-wireless-mechanical-keyboard?variant=32187465465945&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the Keychron K2 (hot-swappable) Wireless Keyboard with brown switches.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick breakdown of the keyboard:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hot-swappable: switches can be changed out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;brown switches: tactile, but not clicky (they give feedback when computer registers the keystroke, so you don’t have to press all the way down)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrow board: pretty similar in size to a keyboard on a 15” laptop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;function keys: programmable (e.g. for media volume, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wireless &amp;amp; wired: wireless for most use; wired when I forget to recharge it (with a USB-c connection!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;things i don’t care about but others do: rgb lighting, slightly fuzzy text on the keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should arrive in a week or so! I’ll update this post with a review of the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hole just deepens from here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/listing/799166246/salmon-sushi-keycaps-handmade-resin?ga_order=most_relevant&amp;amp;ga_search_type=all&amp;amp;ga_view_type=gallery&amp;amp;ga_search_query=keycaps&amp;amp;ref=sr_gallery-1-32&amp;amp;organic_search_click=1&amp;amp;cns=1&quot;&gt;check&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/listing/770063902/konfection-keycaps?ga_order=most_relevant&amp;amp;ga_search_type=all&amp;amp;ga_view_type=gallery&amp;amp;ga_search_query=keycaps&amp;amp;ref=sr_gallery-1-47&amp;amp;organic_search_click=1&quot;&gt;out&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/listing/854677629/resin-keycap-handmade-artisan-keycap?ga_order=most_relevant&amp;amp;ga_search_type=all&amp;amp;ga_view_type=gallery&amp;amp;ga_search_query=keycaps&amp;amp;ref=sr_gallery-2-1&amp;amp;organic_search_click=1&amp;amp;frs=1&quot;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/listing/830651978/cheese-burger-keycap?ga_order=most_relevant&amp;amp;ga_search_type=all&amp;amp;ga_view_type=gallery&amp;amp;ga_search_query=keycaps&amp;amp;ref=sr_gallery-3-16&amp;amp;organic_search_click=1&amp;amp;cns=1&amp;amp;col=1&quot;&gt;keycaps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elizabeth Case</name></author><category term="tools" /><category term="keyboard" /><category term="tech" /><category term="tools" /><summary type="html">I went down a narrow but deep rabbit hole this last weekend, after my partner’s five-year old (external) Apple keyboard crapped out on me. My laptop keyboard has been going down the drain for a while now too – it’s a 2016 Macbook Pro, which has the now-outdated butterfly keys that are notorious for breaking. My a and e keys fall out regularly now, and the rest of the keyboard is on its way.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/keychronk2.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/keychronk2.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Black Point Trailhead</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/BlackPointTrailhead" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Black Point Trailhead" /><published>2020-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/BlackPointTrailhead</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/BlackPointTrailhead">&lt;p&gt;All day I thought this was called the Black &lt;em&gt;Sand&lt;/em&gt; Point Trailhead, but anyways that would have been a misnomer – no sand here! The rocks haven’t yet been worn down by time and water yet, still the rocky, chunky, hard wholes that makes up much of the rugged and beloved Rhode Island coastline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t initially going to include this in the weird walks since this trailhead gets a 4.8 star review on Google Maps accompanied by such praise as “Simply put…. Rhode Island at its best…”. Well Brett, we’ll have to agree to disagree on this one. It is most certainly a weird walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the main trail fifty feet past the sign post and then veer left down an uninspiring path of bramble. Welcome to your walk! On your left, the sound of rushing…. cars, and on your right, a vague whirring that could be the ocean. But you won’t get more than a glimpse for a quarter of a mile or so, when, well past a breach in an old stone wall, the trail abruptly u-turns, taking you fifty feet closer as the crow flies to the water. But still, a tangle of brambles blocks your view of the shoreline, and you are left to contemplate slight movements that may be sparrows in the underbrush. All you get for another quarter mile is a glimpse of expansive blue, or the hard line of the horizon Why did they design the walk this way? Anyways, relish the living – before you see any of the water; can you feel it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, you’ll meet with the path you started on at a T. Continue straight on, it’s about to get good! To your left, a quick view point. Move along! There’s better views down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The path itself is an ambling, grainy, muddy cut about the width of a car; plenty of room for pandemic etiquette (useful, given all the half-masked children). Soon, from behind the tangled, spike-studded vines, the primary attraction: a large sandy-colored boulder, gorgeously fronted by a flat reservoir of water, and framed by a wide rocky beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you continue down the path, you’ll get a glimpse of Scarborough State Beach, and beyond, Point Judith, particularly beautiful when obscured by a late afternoon fog and a gentle setting sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I moved past the best of it and chose a seat on a large flat boulder maybe twenty feet up from the crashing ocean. Waves 2-6 feet tall crashed and foamed, throwing spray up loudly and joyously. To the right, glimpses of beach and civilization; to the left, Black Point. And in front, “the heart of the great ocean sends a thrilling pulse through me”^[Henry Wadsworth Longfellow].&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elizabeth Case</name></author><category term="weirdwalksinRI" /><category term="weirdwalks" /><category term="travel" /><category term="rhode-island" /><summary type="html">All day I thought this was called the Black Sand Point Trailhead, but anyways that would have been a misnomer – no sand here! The rocks haven’t yet been worn down by time and water yet, still the rocky, chunky, hard wholes that makes up much of the rugged and beloved Rhode Island coastline</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The West Greenwich Sand Dunes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/WestGreenwichSandDunes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The West Greenwich Sand Dunes" /><published>2020-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/WestGreenwichSandDunes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/WestGreenwichSandDunes">&lt;p&gt;An expanse of coarse sand that serves up a distinct first impression of “toxic wasteland” or “nuclear storage site”, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps?q=west+greenwich+sand+dunes&amp;amp;um=1&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjxuNSrssvtAhVouVkKHTDbAk0Q_AUoAXoECBUQAw&quot;&gt;West Greenwich Sand Dunes&lt;/a&gt; transport you and your family to the post-apocalypse. In other words, the perfect place to go for a walk in 2020!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an official entrance and parking lot, but I and a few others chose to park on a turnoff off Hopkins Hill Road. I recommend this approach because it drops you right out on top of the eastern set of dunes. Big signs warn that hunter orange is required. Approximately two of the eight people and one of the three dogs I saw were wearing orange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short (20 feet) wooded path opens up into the sandy expanse. The other set of dunes, due west from where I’m standing, hunch in the distance, oddly geometric with flat tops and steep sides. Winding stripes of snow linger in the small undulations left by dirt bikes and ATVs, which provide just enough change in aspect to protect the snow from the late-afternoon sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wander south across the eastern dunes until I reached the tallest one. The sun shines brightly, glinting off the quartz in the sand, not enough to warm you up but enough to make you squint. The slope beckons, and with an imagined yell, I sprint down it, arms swinging wildly, feet kicking up dust, almost floating, losing control of my self and releasing the rage and resignation of this pandemic year. The flat bottom comes up too quickly, and I wheel and skid to a stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the base of the dune, stones have been laid into a fire pit and the letter S. I turn around and trudge back up the sand, embracing the sisyphean: a reckless sprint down, a grunting climb up, over and over. The first time up the hill is the hardest, then your feet slowly carve in stair steps: our present selves setting up the success of our future efforts. Even if the dream is to throw yourself back down the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warm enough now to shed my jacket, I set my sites on the western dunes. To get there, I have to cross a borderland of sandy expanse to reach the knife-edge of a scraggly grassland with three roads cutting through it. Left, middle, right? I choose what’s right in front of me, so head down the middle road, green grass poking through the tire treads, my browned-white Keds sucking the wet mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an interminable amount of time, dazed and glazed, I find myself at the other edge of the grassland. Ahead, a black shape on the sand that looks like the burnt wreckage of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wavyguys.com/&quot;&gt;WavyGuy&lt;/a&gt;. I squint and approach. I have a weird vision that it’s a large snake, coiled and anticipatory. The mirage clears into three charcoaled logs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe because they are shaded, but these dunes don’t provide the same pleasure even though they are taller. I walk up one, hesitating at a piece of pink quartz, picking it up and running my thumb across it’s smoothed face. The place feels unnatural enough that I leave the stone on the mountain. At the top, I find the steepest point. I charge down, and I’m ready to head for home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elizabeth Case</name></author><category term="weirdwalksinRI" /><category term="weirdwalks" /><category term="travel" /><category term="rhode-island" /><summary type="html">An expanse of coarse sand that serves up a distinct first impression of “toxic wasteland” or “nuclear storage site”, the West Greenwich Sand Dunes transport you and your family to the post-apocalypse. In other words, the perfect place to go for a walk in 2020!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Acing the NSF GRFP Personal Statement</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/GRFPPersonalStatement" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Acing the NSF GRFP Personal Statement" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/GRFPPersonalStatement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/GRFPPersonalStatement">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsfgrfp.org/&quot;&gt;NSF GRFP&lt;/a&gt; is a trial-by-fire rite of passage for many graduate students. It is a five-year fellowship that comes with three years of funding and some other perks, including the GROW (international research exchange) and GRIP (national research internships) programs. It can open a lot of doors – allowing you freedom in what you research and helping gain entrance into programs that may not have otherwise have promised full funding. I applied twice – first, as an incoming student, and then a first-year student in my first attempt at a PhD (more on that later). I’ve been a fellow since 2016, and have edited many statements since. This post is a compilation of that experience. Here are links to: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Elizabethcase/elizabethcase.github.io/blob/master/assets/docs/Case_PersonalStatement_final_2015.pdf?raw=true&quot;&gt;personal statement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Elizabethcase/elizabethcase.github.io/blob/master/assets/docs/Case_ResearchProposal_final_2015.pdf?raw=true&quot;&gt;research statement&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to share these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we’re going to focus on the personal statement, which is all about building yourself up. Some notes on the research statement will follow soon. And if you need any help, feel free to reach out to me by email or on twitter: @elizabeth_case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview-of-the-grfps-personal-statement&quot;&gt;Overview of the GRFP’s Personal Statement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are the future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goal is to make reviewers think you are a “future STEM leader”. To put it transactionally, your goal is to convince NSF of a return-on-investment. You need to show a proven record of success, clear access to resources, and the discipline, enthusiasm, and clarity to put that experience and those resources toward answering your field’s biggest questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tons of applicants are qualified, but they are only &lt;em&gt;vaguely&lt;/em&gt; qualified&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to convince NSF that you are all these things is by being explicit. By explicit, I mean you need to quantify your successes, exchange adjectives for specific examples, name names, and write your non-linear, messy life into a clean, obvious narrative. Each sentence should have a purpose — state an achievement, summarize the coming paragraph, provide vivid imagery or examples to draw in readers and remember you by, etc. Especially in the research statement, each sentence should relate back to one of the five criteria used to assess you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also show NSF how “future STEM leader” you are by paying really close attention to what NSF wants. What they say they want is: 2 pages for your research statement and 3 pages for your personal statement. Don’t exceed this. For your research statement, title or bold sections about intellectual merit and broader impact. Look up what these statements mean to NSF; they’re laid out in the call for applications (the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/pubs/2020/nsf20587/nsf20587.htm&quot;&gt;program solicitation&lt;/a&gt; ← read this!”). For your personal statement, you also need intellectual merit and broader impact references, as well as sections about “personal, relevant background, and future goals”. Just make it easy on the reviewers, who are going to be exhausted and bored by the time they read your application, by creating headings with those words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specific-writing-tips&quot;&gt;Specific Writing Tips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build yourself up&lt;/strong&gt;. You don’t have a knack for something, you have excelled at it. You don’t love what you do, you have spent every summer sweating in 100 degree humidity chewed by mosquitoes to collect sedimentary samples that have never been looked at before. You haven’t changed your mind, each step you took led you directly to the next step. Is life this clean? No. Should we have to turn our lives into an easy narrative? No. Unfortunately, though, that’s the game we play right now. Also, remember that everything in your essay should be there to convince NSF that you have &lt;em&gt;already succeeded&lt;/em&gt; (and show remarkable promise), and so are a safe bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk the talk&lt;/strong&gt;. Know the vocabulary of your field, and of academia. This is where (I hope) your adviser (or potential adviser) can come in with help. The most bullshit review of my NSF GRFP application was that I needed to learn “the (insert field) culture”. This is totally unquantifiable and not at all what reviewers are supposed to be looking for but my point is that if you nail the vocabulary, reviewers won’t have to work to understand you, and that gives you an advantage because they can spend more time thinking about how great you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t give reviewers any reason to doubt you&lt;/strong&gt;. Lots of super qualified students are applying for this fellowship. Don’t seed readers with a reason to weed you out. So: don’t self-deprecate, don’t talk not enjoying something, don’t take things smaller than they are (e.g. “stints” are jobs) &amp;amp; rework your failures as stepping stones. There are, of course, exceptions — if for some reason, these are key to your personal story — but in my experience, almost everything can be reworked into a positive attribute, experience, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, this is &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; personal statement. Don’t spend it talking about how great other people are. Other people are great, and collaborations and advisers are key to success and should be highlighted — but you really are writing this to convince people of &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; worth, and three pages is not a lot of time to do that. Focus on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-suggestions-to-keep-in-mind&quot;&gt;Other suggestions to keep in mind:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read through the solicitation (do this!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;grammar and spelling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bold important statements (but use this selectively)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;forego 150 words and add a few photos of yourself. This makes your application personal and memorable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;avoid clichés&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;do outreach, and include descriptions of it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you’re going to try to be funny, you better a) make sure you’re funny and b) be extremely tasteful about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;but do try to evoke a bit of emotion here and there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Elizabeth Case</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="GRFP" /><category term="fellowships" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">The NSF GRFP is a trial-by-fire rite of passage for many graduate students. It is a five-year fellowship that comes with three years of funding and some other perks, including the GROW (international research exchange) and GRIP (national research internships) programs. It can open a lot of doors – allowing you freedom in what you research and helping gain entrance into programs that may not have otherwise have promised full funding. I applied twice – first, as an incoming student, and then a first-year student in my first attempt at a PhD (more on that later). I’ve been a fellow since 2016, and have edited many statements since. This post is a compilation of that experience. Here are links to: personal statement and research statement. Feel free to share these.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">About the Author</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/about-the-author" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About the Author" /><published>2020-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about-the-author</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/about-the-author">&lt;p&gt;Hello! I’m Elizabeth Case. I’m a scientist, writer, and educator. Currently I’m working on my PhD at Columbia University and the Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory. I’m the co-founder of &lt;a href=&quot;www.cycleforscience.org&quot;&gt;Cycle for Science&lt;/a&gt;. I have been published in Scientific American, the State of the Planet, and more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elizabeth Case</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="about" /><summary type="html">Hello! I’m Elizabeth Case. I’m a scientist, writer, and educator. Currently I’m working on my PhD at Columbia University and the Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory. I’m the co-founder of Cycle for Science. I have been published in Scientific American, the State of the Planet, and more.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/alaska_headshot.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/alaska_headshot.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>